Guide to the Scott and Gary Show Archive ca. 1983-1989 MSS 247
Fales Library and Special Collections
Scott and Gary Show Archive
ca. 1983-1989
MSS 247
Fales Library and Special Collections
4.0 boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Arrangement note
The collection is organized into two series:
Series I: Informational Binders
Series II: Video recordings
Scope and Content note
The Scott and Gary Show Archive comprises materials related to the cable-access show, produced and hosted by Scott Lewis and Gary Winter, that ran from 1983 to 1989. Materials include videotapes of the show; photocopies of a chronology of the series, episode descriptions, correspondence, clippings, and photographs; and videotapes of Jeff Krulik's "A Tribute to the Scott and Gary Show", their appearance on the CBS-TV sitcom "Kate and Allie", and an in-depth video interview with the show's creators.
The collection is arranged into two series:
Series I: Informational Binders. This series contains photocopies of a chronology of the series, episode descriptions, correspondence, clippings, and photographs.
Series II: Video. This series is divided into two subseries. Subseries A contains access copies for the researcher. At present, access copies have not been created for all material. Please contact a Fales archivist. Subseries B contains original video elements.
Historical Note
The Scott and Gary Show was a cable access variety show that ran from 1983 to 1989 and featured punk and indie bands, live audience dance parties, and comedy skits. Created and hosted by Scott Lewis and Gary Winter, the show was filmed in New York City from 1983 to 1986 and, at the invitation of cable access producer Jeff Krulik, in the Washington DC metro area, from 1986 to 1989.
The show is notable for early appearances of bands such as the Butthole Surfers and the Beastie Boys (who appear with drummer Kate Schellenbach, later of Luscious Jackson). Other musical guests include the Ben Vaughn Combo, Raunch Hands, Half Japanese, Shockabilly, and Velvet Monkeys.
Separated Materials
Twenty videotapes were returned to donor Scot Lewis in September 2012. These deaccessioned materials are indicated in the finding aid. All videotapes were preserved by Fales, except for appearance on "Kate and Allie" television series. The repository holds preservation masters and access viewing copies for all other deaccessioned tapes.
Cable television |x Access.; Rock groups.; Videocassettes.
- Series I: Informational Binders
  - Scott and Gary Show Informational Binder I, 1983-2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Scott and Gary Show Informational Binder II, 1983-2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Video recordings
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original material may not be available for consultation. Please ask a Fales archivist for access. Also see Series II: Subseries A: Video Access Copies
  - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 102--Beastie Boys, January 29, 1984 (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0001)
    General note
    Original format: 1" video
    Duration: unknown
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 102--Beastie Boys [MASTER], January 29, 1984 (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0094)
    Original format: U-Matic
    Duration: 28 minutes
    Separated Materials
    Videotape returned to donor.
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 103--1/2 Japanese, February 4, 1984 (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0104)
    Existence and Location of Copies note
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0139.
    Originla format: U-Matic
  - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 103--1/2 Japanese, February 4, 1984 (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0002)
    Duration: Unknown
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 104--R. Stevie Moore [MASTER], April 1, 1984 (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0098)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0121.
    Duration: 30 minutes
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 105-- The Raunch Hands, April 29, 1984 (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0100)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0127.
  - The Scott and Gary Show--The Raunch Hands, April 29, 1984 (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0009)
  - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 105--Curtis A, May 26, 1984 (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0004)
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 106--Curtis A [MASTER], May 26, 1984 (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0096)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0115.
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 202--The Johnsons [MASTER], January 11, 1985 (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0101)
    Acces DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0130.
  - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 202--The Johnsons, January 11, 1985 (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0006)
  - (DEACCESSIONED) "Scott and Gary #10" -- Woofing Cookies, March 26, 1985 (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0103)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0136.
  - (DEACCESSIONED) Scott and Gary #11--Shockabilly [MASTER], March 30,1985 (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0099)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0124.
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show (Maryland Shoot)-- Episode 14--The Rhomboids, July 12, 1986 (Box 2, Media ID: 241.0011)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #247.0040.
    Original format: 3/4" Umatic
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show (Maryland Shoot)--The Velvet Monkeys, July 12, 1986 (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0012)
    Access DVD available. Please request Access DVD #247.0043.
  - Scott and Gary Show--Shockabilly, August 19, 1986 (Box 2, Media ID 247.0036)
    Duration: 32 minutes
  - Elvis #1, Tape 1 of 7, August 1, 1987 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0017)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0066.
    Original format: Betacam
  - Elvis #2, Tape 2 of 7, August 1, 1987 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0018)
    Access DVD available. Please request DVD #247.0069.
  - Elvis #3, Tape 3 of 7, August 1, 1987 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0019)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0072.
  - Elvis #4, Tape 4 of 7, August 1, 1987 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0020)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0075.
  - Elvis #5, Tape 5 of 7, August 1, 1987 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0021)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0078.
  - Elvis #6, Tape 6 of 7, August 1, 1987 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0022)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0081.
  - Elvis #7, Tape 7 of 7, August 1, 1987 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0023)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0084.
    Arrangement note
    Material arranged by format and by chronological order.
  - Scott and Gary Interviews, 2/2000; Disc 1 of 3, February 2000 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0029)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0087.
    Original format: DVD-R
    Duration: 1 hour 5 minutes
  - Scott and Gary Interviews, 2/2000; Disc 2 of 3, February 2000 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0030)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0090
  - Scott and Gary Interviews, 2/2000; Disc 3 of 3, February 2000 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0031)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0093.
  - Scott and Gary Go To VH1, 2001 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0028)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0061.
    Original format: VHS-C
    Duration: 29 minutes
  - Altar boys, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0034)
  - Before They Were Rock Stars, #46, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0026)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0058.
    Original format: VHS
  - Jeff Krulik Presents: A Tribute to The Scott and Gary Show, June 15, 2004 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0027)
    Duration: 1 hour 30 minutes
  - Jeff Krulik Presents a Tribute to the Scott and Gary Show, June 15, 2004 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0033)
    Access copy available. Please request access DVD #247.0063.
    Original format: Betacam SP
  - N.D.F., undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0037)
    Duration: 1 hour
  - (DEACCESSIONED)Scott and Gary on Kate and Allie, undated (Box 4, Media ID: 247.0032)
    Videotape returned to donor. Fales does not have this title preserved.
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show--Beatnik Fly, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0016)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0055.
    TRT: 00:57:30
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show--Ben Vaughn and Aldo Jones, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0015)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0052.
  - The Scott and Gary Show--Clintons, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0007)
  - The Scott and Gary Show--Danny Barfman, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0025)
    Original format: Betamax
  - The Scott and Gary Show--Elvis, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0024)
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show--Das Yahoos, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0014)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0049.
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 18--Beatoes, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0013)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0046.
  - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 101--Ben Vaughn, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0035)
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 101--Ben Vaughn, undated (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0095)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0112.
  - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 104--Stevee Moore, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0003)
  - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 201--The Butthole Surfers, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0005)
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 201--The Butthole Surfers [MASTER], undated (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0106)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0145.
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 203--No King, undated (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0105)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0142.
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 212--The Alterboys [MASTER], undated (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0102)
    Access DVD available. Please access DVD #247.0133.
  - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 213--The Clintons, undated (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0097)
    Access DVD available. Please request access DVD #247.0118.
  - The Scott and Gary Show--No King, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0008)
  - The Scott and Gary Show--Woofing Cookies, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0010)